const e="englishlit",o=200,a=25,t=[{id:124,question:"A novel that has a very strong presence of the supernatural is known as ______ ",option:{a:"faction  ",b:"gothic  ",c:"travel tale  ",d:"fairy novel "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:125,question:"In a tragic-comedy, the unknotting of the plot, the resolution of the mystery and the resolution of the misunderstanding is called  ",option:{a:"exposition   ",b:"denouement   ",c:"catharsis  ",d:"hubris"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:126,question:"The exclusive right given to authors to protect their works from unlawful production or reproduction is   ",option:{a:"A copyright  ",b:"an authority to write  ",c:"an author’s right   ",d:"a constitutional provision "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:127,question:"An epic deals with  ",option:{a:"humour  ",b:"tragedy  ",c:"gothic  ",d:"hero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:128,question:"The sudden revelation of events as they happen is called  ",option:{a:"epiphany  ",b:"revelation  ",c:"relay-events  ",d:"resonance "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:129,question:"Comic relief is used in a work of art to  ",option:{a:"to suspend disbelief  ",b:"to maneuver the portal of narration  ",c:"to create chiaroscuro  ",d:"to suspend to tension "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:130,question:"The image in this excerpt suggest ",option:{a:"happiness  ",b:"sorrow ",c:"anger  ",d:"kindness"},section:`(Extract for question)I thank you God for creating me black
For making of me
Porter of all sorrows
Setting on my mind
The world
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:131,question:"The world as used above is an example of  ",option:{a:"irony  ",b:"metaphor ",c:"exaggeration  ",d:"parody "},section:`(Extract for question)I thank you God for creating me black
For making of me
Porter of all sorrows
Setting on my mind
The world
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:132,question:"This extract is an example of  ",option:{a:"dirge  ",b:"satire  ",c:"ode  ",d:"sonnet"},section:`(Extract for question)
Agosu, if you go tell them,
Tell Nyidevu, Kpeti, and Kove
That they have done us evil;
Tell them house is falling 
And the tree in the fence
Have been eaten by termites 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:133,question:"The general  idea in the extract is ",option:{a:"neglect  ",b:"praise  ",c:"ridicule  ",d:"worship"},section:`(Extract for question)
Agosu, if you go tell them,
Tell Nyidevu, Kpeti, and Kove
That they have done us evil;
Tell them house is falling 
And the tree in the fence
Have been eaten by termites 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:134,question:"  The central motif in this excerpt is  ",option:{a:"religious  ",b:"pride  ",c:"poverty  ",d:"deceit "},section:`(Extract for question )
Blessed Nigerians,
Who eat pestilence to sleep
Blessed the poor 
Who inherit thorns. . . . . . 
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:135,question:"The extract is an example of  ",option:{a:"pun  ",b:"hyperbole  ",c:"Irony  ",d:"parody"},section:`(Extract for question )
Blessed Nigerians,
Who eat pestilence to sleep
Blessed the poor 
Who inherit thorns. . . . . . 
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:136,question:"“Your hand is heavy, Night, upon by brow” is an example of  ",option:{a:"hyperbole  ",b:"onomatopoeia  ",c:"apostrophe  ",d:"oxymoron "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:137,question:"From this passage, the people that the writer admire are  ",option:{a:"poor  ",b:"brilliant   ",c:"rich   ",d:"unassuming "},section:`(Extract for question)
The human beings who I most admire are those without sterling qualities but are extraordinary in their ordinariness, the unsung heroes who will never be in the limelight or boulevard of fame, people who do great things when no one is watching or those who are not marked with the maple leaves of chieftaincy titles. They only wear fate, hard work, perseverance, anonymity and time. Yet, they are passionate, caring, visionary, sincere, determined and honest. These qualities mold those that are special without being aware. I strive to stay true to some of these qualities that I admire. To find a person with a few of these qualities is rare these days. To know someone who has all of them is amazing and a true blessing. [Excerpt from Tomorrow Left Us Yesterday-Tayo Olafioye]
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:138,question:"The writer informs the reader that people with good qualities are  ",option:{a:"many  ",b:"few  ",c:"fearful  ",d:"famous"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:139,question:"Aaron’s brother who trains as an accountant is  ",option:{a:"George  ",b:"Awere  ",c:"Owusu  ",d:"Kofi"},section:"Question is based on Joe de Graft’s Sons and daughters",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:140,question:"Which of the following is true of the Awere?  ",option:{a:"He is the fiancé of Maanan  ",b:"He is a chartered accountant   ",c:"He wins a scholarship to Goldsmith College  ",d:"He wants to study dance and choreography "},section:"Question is based on Joe de Graft’s Sons and daughters",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:141,question:"The conflict in the play centres around  ",option:{a:"gender  ",b:"generation  ",c:"religion  ",d:"ethnicity "},section:"Question is based on Joe de Graft’s Sons and daughters",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:142,question:" The text of Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet is sourced in ",option:{a:"1623 second Folio  ",b:"1590 rehearsal guide  ",c:"1599 Quarto  ",d:"1616 manuscript "},section:"Question is drawn from William Shakespeare’s ROMEO and JULIET",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:143,question:"“There’s no trust No faith, no honesty in men, all perjured, All forsworn, all naught, all dissembles” The speaker of the above excerpt is ",option:{a:"Nurse  ",b:"Juliet  ",c:"Balthasaar  ",d:"Capulet "},section:"Question is drawn from William Shakespeare’s ROMEO and JULIET",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:144,question:"Another Suitor of Juliet in the play is  ",option:{a:"Mercutio  ",b:"Gregory  ",c:"Duke  ",d:"Paris"},section:"Question is drawn from William Shakespeare’s ROMEO and JULIET",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:145,question:"In the novel, the Ministry that is responsible for news, entertainment and fine arts in the Ministry of  ",option:{a:"Peace  ",b:"Love  ",c:"Plenty  ",d:"Truth"},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eight Four",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:146,question:"The Ministry of Plenty in the Novel is responsible for  ",option:{a:"War  ",b:"economic affairs  ",c:"Population  ",d:"Agriculture "},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eight Four",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:147,question:"The national day in The Old Man and the Medal is  ",option:{a:"1st of October  ",b:"27th of May  ",c:"12th June  ",d:"14th July"},section:`Question is based on Ferdinand Oyono’s
The Old Man and medal and The joys of motherhood   
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:148,question:"In Joys of Motherhood, Dr Meers is  ",option:{a:"Nnaife’s master  ",b:"Nnuego’s uncle  ",c:"The District Officer  ",d:"An ombudsman"},section:`Question is based on Ferdinand Oyono’s
The Old Man and medal and The joys of motherhood   
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"}],n={subject:e,status:200,total:25,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,o as status,e as subject,a as total};
